CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Name : ASIF KHAN (Ashu)

Address : 58, West End Colony, National Highway-24, Bareilly (U.P) India

Tel. No : (+91) 78424-72764, 98488-36758

E-mail : asif.khan530@gmail.com, bajpai.ashu83@gmail.com

Gender : Male

Date of birth : 23 October 1985

Marital Status : Single

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To use my skills & knowledge by regularly coping with new Technologies for serving the organization in efficient and effective manner.

SUMMARY OF KNOWLEDGE AS SOFTWARE AND WEB DEVELOPER

- → 5+ years of experience in Android and Iphone Application Development.
- → Experience in Cross Platform (Phonegap) Mobile Application Development.
- → Experience Website Design and Development (PHP & MYSQL).
- → User Interface design using HTML, CSS, Jquery, Jquery Mobile, Photoshop etc.
- → Performing analysis and designing of Mobile Applications.
- → Understanding of complete SDLC.
- → Knowledge of DBMS and RDBMS.
- → Provided training to Corporate clients as Well as College Students on Android Application Development

TRAINING EXPERIENCE

Roles & Responsibilities in Various Organizations as Trainer:

- Created course guides for Mobile Application Development training.
- Provided Mobile Application Development & Training (Android & Cross Platform)
- Giving the basic understanding of Mobile platforms.
- Prepared webinars and student reference materials for quality training.
- Researching new technologies and using them practically.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Organization: - ADS Softek Pvt. Ltd.

Position Held:- Software Engineer & Mobile App Developer

Duration:- Feb 2014 to Present

Roles & Responsibilities:-

- Mobile Application Development & Training (Android & Cloud Computing)
- Working on Mobile Applications for Offshore Clients.
- Researching new technologies and using them practically.

Organization: - Acronym Solutions

Position Held:- Software Engineer & Web Developer **Duration:-** April 2013 to Jan 2014

Roles & Responsibilities:-

- Mobile Application Development & Training (Android & Cloud Computing)
- Working on Mobile Applications for Offshore Clients.
- Researching new technologies and using them practically

Organization: - Quick Response Technology Pvt. Ltd., Noida (India)

Position Held:- Software Engineer & Web Developer **Duration:-** April 2012 to March 2013

Roles & Responsibilities:-

- Mobile Application Development & Training (Android & Cloud Computing)
- Working on Mobile Applications for Offshore Clients.
- Researching new technologies and using them practically

Organization: Satguru Travel & Tourism, Dubai LLC (UAE)

Position Held:- Software Engineer & Web Developer **Duration:-** March 2010 to March 2012

Roles & Responsibilities:-

- Mobile Application Development & Training (Android & Cloud Computing)
- Working on Mobile Applications for Offshore Clients.
- Researching new technologies and using them practically

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Master Degree in Business Administration (MBA)

Field of Study :- Finance & IT

Institute :- International Management Institute, Belgium, Europe

Percentage :- 65 %

Completed :- March, 2010

Master Degree in Computer Science (M.Sc.)

Field of Study :- Computer Science

Institute :- Makhanlal University, Bhopal (MP), India

Percentage :- 74.09 % Completed :- July, 2009

Graduation Degree Computer Application (BCA)

Field of Study :- Computer Application

Institute :- Makhanlal University, Bhopal (MP), India

Percentage :- 73.78 % Completed :- July, 2007

Diploma in Computer Hardware and Networking

Field of Study :- Computer Hardware & Networking
Institute :- Jetking Institute, Bareilly(UP), India

Percentage :- 71 % Completed :- July, 2007

SKILLS/ STRENGTHS

PROJECT DETAILS:-

Role : Website Developer, Designer

Project Type : Software Development of:-

> School Management System for Genius Int. School School Management System for Alma Mater School School Management System for Vidhya Bhawan School

Role : Developer

Mobile Applications:- ERP based Mobile Apps (Connect4M (Cross Platform & Native)), Hire Auto,

Flavorbaba, Heritage Connect4m

PROGRAMMING SKILLS: HTML/XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, Jquery Mobile, Angular JS,PHP/LAMP

(Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP), Bootstrap, Wordpress, AJAX, Adobe Photoshop, Dreamweaver, JavaScript, Joomla, Multimedia Flash, MVC, VB.NET, C, C++ C#, XML, AJAX, IIS, Mobile (Android, Iphone) App Development, Visual Studio, Web Services, Rest WCF Services, JSON,

IBM Worklight, Phonegap,

DATABASE SKILLS SQL Server 2005, SQL Server 2008, MS Access 2010, MYSQL

OTHER SKILLS Testing & Debugging software and website, System Troubleshooting, Network

Management, Router configuration.

INTERPERSONAL Strong team working, leadership, good communication skill, Presentation skills,

Can work under pressure, meet tight deadlines and positive in any situation

appear.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certification in PHP Development.

Certification in Android Applications Development

Microsoft Certified C# Developer.

INDUSTRIAL VISITS

Industry Visit for 15 days of **Belgium**, **Paris & Germany (Europe)**

- Jacques Chocolate Factory (1st Chocolate Factory in World), Belgium.
- Coca Cola Factory, Belgium.
- Port of Antwerp, Belgium
- Guy Delforge Perfume Factory, Germany.
- Education Tour to Paris.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACHIEVEMENTS

- Won prizes in Handwriting, Quiz, Race competition in Inter School Competition.
- 1st Prize in International Knowledge and Science, Test.
- Runner up Prize in Finance Quiz Moz (Finance) organized by IIPM.

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

Travelling, sports, reading, writing poems, listening music and drawing.